well hello everyone interesting how our
以及大家感兴趣的是如何我们
fewer seats are filled than at the
座位少填充比在
beginning of the course so that of
课程 的开始，使中
course we're in the final stretch of
当然我们是在最后阶段
this course you're working on the last
这当然你在最后的工作
lab and the material that we're covering
实验室， 我们正在 覆盖材料
both this lecture and next lecture are
双方本次讲座和下一讲是
not on the exam and you don't need them
不是在考试， 你不需要他们
for your web so at some level you could
为您的 网站，从而在一定 程度 上 你 可以
just tune out and skip it all and if
只是调出并跳过 这一切，如果
your only purpose in taking this course
您只有在参加此课程的目的
is to pass it or to get some grade in it
是通过它或得到一些年级它
and that's it well go ahead tune out but
这就是它也继续 调 出来，但
on the other hand the material we're
另一方面 ， 我们的材料
talking about is very relevant to where
讲的是到 非常相关
computers are today and where they're
电脑是今天，他们是
going in the future and so if you think
打算在未来 ，所以，如果你认为
about the longer term and whatever your
大约 从长远来看 无论你的
investment is in the computer industry
投资是在计算机行业
and computer technology is then I think
与计算机技术是那么我认为
you'll find these very worthwhile but so
你会发现这些非常值得的，但这样
think of this more as the icing on the
认为这更多的是在结冰
cake you've learned the hard stuff
蛋糕，你学过的硬的东西
you've you've done the grinding part and
你，你所做的破碎部和
now you get to thank beyond the sort of
现在你要感谢 超越的那种
narrow confines of the course material
过程中材料的狭窄范围
and and think bigger but that's really
并且，认为大但真的
the way you should be viewing this
你应该 查看此 方式
lecture in the last lecture which will
在讲座上一讲这将
be on Thursday so today what we're going
所以今天我们是什么星期四
to talk about is parallelism and the
谈的是并行和
issue is that that Wow
问题是，那哇
that PowerPoint is a product made by a
PowerPoint将 是由制造的产品
certain company in Seattle that it's not
某公司在 西雅图， 它不
always reliable but the issue is as you
总是可靠的 ，但问题是 ，你
know nowadays when you buy a computer
现在知道 ，当 你买电脑
you don't get just one CPU on the
你 没有得到的只是一个CPU
processor chip you have at least two on
处理器芯片，你至少有两个上
a typical laptop even my phone has two
一个典型的笔记本电脑 ，甚至我的手机有两个
cores in it and as well as four graphics
在其核心，以及四个 图形
processing units and a typical the the
处理单元和一个典型的中
next generation of iPad will be a six
下一代iPad将是 六
core processor so these have become not
核处理器， 所以这些都 成为不
just the sort of specialized domain of
只是那种专业领域的
of high-end machines but actually there
高端机器，但实际上有
all the time and actually we'll talk
所有的时间， 实际上我们将讨论
some next time why is it that instead of
一些下一次那为什么不是
having one fast computer you get to a
有一个快速的电脑，你得到一个
medium size medium performance
中等大小中等性能
processors on a chip or more and that
一个或多个片上，并且处理器
that's actually a really interesting
这 实际上是一个非常有趣的
technology issue that I'll talk about
技术 问题，我要谈谈
next time but it's the way it is so you
接下来的时间，但它是 如此你 的方式
can think of it when you write a program
可以把 它当你写一个程序
and it runs as a single thread then
并且它会作为一个单独的线程则
you're basically not making use of the
你基本上没有利用的
computing resources that you have
你必须计算资源
available to you so the natural thing is
提供给你 这样的东西自然
well could we make our programs run
好，我们可以让我们的程序运行
faster by doing multiple threads so
通过做多线程，以便更快
you've already learned or you're in the
你已经学会或者你在
process of applying a multi-threaded
将多线程 的过程
programming as a way to deal with a
编程的方式来对付
concurrency of external events there's
外部 事件 的并发有
multiple clients who want to make use of
谁想要使用多台客户端
a server and instead of serving one and
和 一个 服务 而不是服务器和
then another and then another if you can
然后又接着 又如果你能
handle them all it's sort of a an
处理它们所有它是一个排序的一个
external use of concurrency but what
外用并发但什么
we'll talk about today is more internal
我们将谈论今天 是更多的 内部
use can I make use of multiple threads
使用我可以利用多线程
running on multiple cores to make a
在 多个内核 上运行，以使
program run a single program run faster
程序运行单个程序的运行速度
and the message behind that is yes but
而背后的消息是肯定的，但
and what I mean is it is truly possible
和我的意思是它 是真正 有可能
and
和
people spend a lot of time making
人们花了很多 时间做
programs run faster by using multiple
程序使用多个跑得更快
threads but it's harder than you'd think
线程，但 比你想象 它很难
it should be and it's fraught with as
它应该 是和它充满了如
you probably already experienced
你可能已经经历
programming bugs but also it's just
编程错误，但 它也只是
really darn hard to get the kind of
真是混账很难得到的那种
performance out of a multi-core
表现出来 的多核心
processor that you should would think
你 应该会觉得处理器
it'd be available so we'll talk about
这将会是可用的，所以我们将谈论
some of that and then we'll finish it up
一些 这一点，那么我们将完成它
a little bit understanding of how how
如何如何一点点的理解
when you're writing concurrent programs
当你写并发程序
you want to think about the state of
你要想想 的状态
memory and how that's the challenge for
内存以及如何这对面临的挑战
multi-core processors or in fact any
多核处理器或任何事实
concurrent concurrent system so there's
同时并发系统，以便有
actually two sources of concurrency on a
并发 上实际上有两个来源
modern processor multiple cores which is
现代处理器的多个核是
you have actually multiple CPUs on a
你有一个实际多个CPU
single chip but there's also something
单芯片但也有一些
called hyper-threading which is in my
所谓超线程这 是我的
experience less useful but let me go
经验少有用的，但让我走
through this so this is what a typical
通过这个所以这是一个典型的
modern processor looks like processor
现代处理器看起来像处理器
chip is that there's actually on a
芯片是实际上有 一个上
single chip there is multiple
单芯片有多个
independent CPUs and each of them has
独立的CPU 和他们每个人都有
some part of the cache hierarchy which
缓存层次结构的某些部分，其
is private to that particular core and
是专用于 特定的核心，
then there is another part of the cache
再有就是缓存的另一部分
hierarchy that's shared across cores and
导致用户在内核和共享层次
then they all have a common interface to
然后，他们都有一个共同的接口
main memory so if these cores are
主内存中，因此如果这些内核是
running and this is what happens to
运行，这是发生了什么
audits they're running programs that are
审计他们正在运行的程序是
completely independent have nothing to
完全独立的没有什么
do with each other then they more or
与对方那么他们更多或
less just exist and run and they're
少只是 存在和运行，他们是
happy as can be they are caching parts
高兴，因为可以为他们缓存部件
of their own state and you know
自己的状态，你知道
sometimes this cache will get polluted
有时这种高速缓存将获得污染
by the junk from other programs in terms
通过从其他方面计划垃圾
of performance but it will matter with
性能，但它会与物质
functionality the trick when you're
功能，当你的伎俩
trying to do multi-core programming as a
尝试 做多核心编程的
parallel computing thing somehow getting
并行计算的东西越来越莫名其妙
all these cores
所有 这些内核
working on parts of different parts of a
工作的不同部分 的零件
single problem in a way that makes it so
在某种程度上 ，使得它如此单一的问题
that you get the performance out of it
你得到的表现 出 它
they don't spend all their time
他们不会把所有的时间
basically arguing with each other about
基本上彼此 谈论争论
who has access to what and also that
谁访问 了 什么，也即
they're not stepping over each other and
他们没有踏过 对方，
messing up each other's state so
搞乱对方的状态，
hyper-threading is a little bit more
超线程是多一点点
into the deep works of how a processor
成怎样的处理器深工程
operates you'll recall from the lecture
进行操作，你会 从这次讲座中 回顾
on performance or what's chapter 5 of
性能或什么的第5章
the book that a modern microprocessor
书上 说一个现代微处理器
looks absolutely nothing like the model
看起来完全 不像模型
that you get by looking at assembly code
你通过看汇编 代码得到
instructions the model of assembly code
指令的汇编代码的模型
is you execute one instruction then you
是你执行一条指令，那么你
execute the next one then you execute
执行下一个，那么你执行
the next one modern processors don't do
下 一个现代的 处理器不做
that at all they haven't done it for
，在所有他们没有 这样做它
well they haven't done it that way for
那么，他们还没有做到这样 的
30 years and since 1995 so since 20
30 年，自1995年以来使20
years they do it in this totally
多年来，他们做这个完全
different way which is sometimes
不同的方式，其是有时
referred to as out of order processing
被称为 乱 序处理的
and so just real quickly the the basic
所以只是真正的快速 的 基本
idea is on the processor chip there's
想法是处理器芯片有上
multiple functional units that are
是多个功能单元
capable of doing different types of
能够做不同类型的
operation these ones for integer
操作这些的整数
arithmetic these ones for floating-point
算术这些的浮点
arithmetic and so forth and then there's
算术来回左右，然后有
separate blocks that interface to the
分离的块该接口到
memory actually to the cache memories
记忆里却到高速缓存存储器
and they're both loading meaning reading
他们俩都加载意义阅读
from the memory and storing writing out
从 内存和 存储写出
to memory but these units are sort of
到内存中，但这些单位有几分
operate independently and what happens
独立运作，会发生什么
is there's a block of logic which is
是还有的逻辑块，其是
actually an enormous with huge block of
实际上是一个巨大的 具有巨大的块
logic in the next 86 processor that
在接下来的86处理器的逻辑
reads the instructions out of the
读取指令出的
instruction stream rips them apart into
指令流撕裂它们分开成
little pieces keeps track of data
小件 跟踪 数据
dependencies and control dependencies
依赖和控制依赖
and then schedules all the various
然后安排所有不同
operations in your program on these
在您对这些程序操作
different functional units so we talked
不同的功能单元，所以我们聊
some about that of in the context of how
一些关于 在怎样的背景下
can
能够
write a program that will sort of
编写一个程序， 将整理的
maximize how much is going on down here
最大限度地提高多少是怎么回事这儿
by writing your code in a particular way
通过一种特殊的方式编写代码
so all this is an introduction to say
所以这一切都是介绍说，
this is how you have to understand what
这是你怎么也得 明白
hyper threading is so in a single
超线程是这样在单一
execution mode there's basically one
执行模式有一个基本
instruction decoder and it has its own
指令解码器，它有它自己的
set of state here its own program
集邦这里了自己的方案
counter its own queue of operations that
应对其自身业务的队列
it's already decoded and haven't
它已经解码，并没有
completed yet it has its own set of
完成但它有它自己的一套
registers they're actually not
登记他们其实并没有
registered like you'd expect they're
注册像你期望他们
they're highly virtualized registers but
他们是高度虚拟化的寄存器， 但
all this state is there to help to
这一切的状态是有帮助 到
service the execution of one thread of
服务的 一个线程的执行
execution with hyper threading basically
执行与超线程基本上
what you do is the idea that is to say
你要做的就是就是说想法
90% of all programs don't really make
90％ 的所有程序都不能很好的
use of all these functional units
利用所有这些功能单元的
especially if you're blocking on a load
特别是 如果你阻止的负载
because there's a miss in a cache then
因为有在缓存中的缺失则
all these arithmetic units are sitting
所有这些计算单元都坐在
there without any useful work to do well
有没有任何有用的工作要做好
and so why don't we just double up or
所以我们为什么不只是加倍或
quadruple upper K times up the state
四倍上 K次向上的状态
associated with the decoding and control
与解码和控制相关联的
parts of the program so that you can
该计划的一部分，这样就 可以
have multiple threads running and
在运行 多线程 和
sharing these functional units among
之间共享这些功能单元
each other so they're operating really
对方所以他们真的工作
independently their states are not
独立的状态不是
intertwined but they're sort of making
交织在一起，但他们那种使
more use of the available hardware for
更多地利用 现有硬件的
performing functions and so that's
执行功能，所以这是
called hyper threading that's an Intel
所谓超线程这是英特尔
term you also sometimes hear call SMT
学期，你也有时会 听到叫SMT
simultaneous multi-threading and in my
同时多线程和我
experience and we'll see here the
经验，我们会看到这里的
numbers it doesn't really make that big
数它并没有真正做出 大
a difference but it turns out to be in
有差别 ，但它原来是 在
the sort of large picture things a
那种大画面的东西
relatively inexpensive feature for them
对他们来说相对便宜的功能
to throw on to processors and so they do
扔在处理器和让他们做
it
它
and so nowadays at least with an x86
所以现在至少有86
processor usually have to weigh
处理器通常必须权衡
hyper-threading in them so given that if
在他们超线程所以考虑到，如果
you look at our shark machines which are
你看看我们的鲨鱼机有哪些
a little bit old there's sort of 2010
有点老有那种2010
era machine but they were high-end
时代的机器，但他们是 高端
machines in their day and so they still
每天在他们的机器，所以他们仍然
actually are more powerful than what
实际上比更强大的 是什么
you'd buy as say a desktop and way more
你会买是说一个桌面和方式更多
powerful than as a laptop that you'd get
不是作为一台笔记本电脑，你会得到强大
today so they're actually pretty decent
所以今天它们实际上是相当不错的
machines and actually we'll talk next
机其实我们接下来会说话
time about why computers aren't a lot
时间为什么电脑还不是很多
faster than they were five years ago
比 五年前更快
that's actually an interesting
这实际上有趣
technology thing so they they're server
技术的事情，所以他们 他们是服务器
class machines so they have multiple
一流的设备， 使 他们有多个
cores and they have eight of them which
内核，他们有他们的其中八个
is a lot you can buy ten core machines
是很多 ，你 可以买 十个核机
x86 machines on a single chip but I
一个单一的芯片，但我在x86机器上
don't think you can get more yet so
不要以为你可以得到更多的却又 如此
these were fairly advanced machine of
这些人的比较先进的机
their day and they also have two-way
他们的一天，他们也有 双向
hyper threading so in theory you should
超线程所以理论上你应该
be able to get 16 independent threads
能够获得 16个独立 线程
running sort of 16 way parallelism
运行排序 16 路并行 的
potentially out of a program if you can
可能出程序的 ，如果你能
keep everything working and keep bad
让一切工作，并保持不错
things from happening
从发生的事情
so let's give a really trivial
所以让我们给一个真是小巫见大巫
application one that should be very
应用一个应该 是很
simple to make run in parallel that says
简单的 并行，使跑，说
imaginary we want to sum up the numbers
想象我们要总结的数字
between 0 and n minus 1 which is by the
介于0和n 减 1，其由
way a really stupid thing to do because
方式真正 愚蠢的事情，因为
there's a very simple closed-form
有一个很简单的封闭形式
formula for it which is good in the
式为它是在良好
sense that will let us check our work
感觉这将让我们检查我们的工作
but it's a completely stupid application
但它是一个 完全愚蠢的程序
but it just shows you this idea and so
但它只是说明 你这个想法 等
what we're just going to do is is block
我们只是要做的是就是块
off if we have n way parallelism we're
关闭，如果我们有N 路并行我们
just going to split our range of numbers
只是要分裂 我们的数字范围
n ways and just have a single thread sum
n路，只是有一个线程 总和
up one n of the numbers and then they'll
了一个n的数字，然后他们会
collectively sum together the result in
合加在一起的 结果
some way or another so this is about as
一些这样或那样所以这大约是
easy a parallel program as you could
易并行程序 ，你可能
imagine
想像
so let's do a one version which is said
所以让我们做了一个版本，据说这是
well gee I understand how to use threads
以及哎呀我知道如何使用线程
P threads and I know about these things
P个线程，我知道这些事情
called semaphores or mutual exclusion so
所谓的信号灯或互斥如此
what I'll do is just all all love have
我要做的只是一切的一切都爱
one place in memory where I'm collecting
在内存中的一个地方，我收集
the sum over all n values and for a
在所有n值和一个 总和
thread to be able to add to that if it
线程能够 ，如果将其 添加 到
it will lock it it will get a mutual
它会锁定它，它会得到一个相互
exclusive access to it increment it and
它独占访问 增加它和
then unlock it and we'll just let all
然后打开它，我们就会让所有的
the threads go helter-skelter locking
线程去仓惶 锁定
and unlocking this so the code for that
和解锁这使该代码
is pretty easy to write it it's here's
很容易 把它写它在这里是
the the code and of course all threaded
该代码，当然所有螺纹
code looks a lot messier than you think
代码看上去混乱比你想象
it should but in the end it's a fairly
它应该但最终这是一个相当
straightforward code so in particular
简单的代码，以便在特定
this is the thread routine is passing
这 是线程程序传递
through this weird bargue
通过这个奇怪的 bargue
pea structure that you do with with
豌豆结构，你用做
threads the way you pass arguments to a
线程的方式传递参数给
thread routine but basically it's
线程程序，但基本上它是
figuring out where is the start and end
搞清楚在哪里开始和结束
range of the numbers then adding a
数的范围内再加入
for all I between the start and before
对于所有的开始 之间 还没等我
the end I'll lock that acquire a
最后，我会锁定该 获得
semaphore lock I'll increment this
旗语锁我就会增加 一次
global sum and then I'll release the
全球总和，然后我就会解除
lock okay so pretty much the style of
锁定好了，所以相当多的风格
code that you've been working with and
你一直使用 的代码 和
what you find is actually this is really
你发现了什么是其实 这 是 真的
a bad idea so running as a single thread
一个坏主意 ， 所以运行作为单线程
it takes 51 seconds to do that it would
它需要51秒做到这一点它会
be by the way if you didn't lock and
是的方式，如果你没有锁定和
unlock because it's only one thread
解锁，因为它只有一个线程
you'd blow this away it would take just
你吹这个客场将采取只
a couple seconds so and then you see as
几秒钟左右，然后你看到的
you add more threads it actually gets
你添加更多的线程，它实际上得到
worse and especially if you jump from
糟糕， 特别是如果你从跳
one to two you increase by a factor nine
一到两个你的一个因素9增加
how much time it takes and it only
它是如何花费的时间也只有它
starts to get better as you get up into
开始得到更好的为你成
eight threads and then it gets worse
八个线程，然后将它变得更糟
again so the reason is that locking and
再这样的原因是锁定和
unlocking is a very time consuming task
解锁是一个非常耗时的任务
and basically you can think of is that
基本上你能想到的是 ，
you if you have that map of the
你如果有地图
multi-core processors with all their
与所有多核处理器的
private caches in one shared cache these
在一个共享的缓存私有的高速缓存这些
threads are basically fighting with each
螺纹基本上每个战斗
other for control for that one memory
另一个用于为一个存储器控制
address that they that they're
解决他们，他们是
incrementing and it has to grab the
递增和它抢
control away from one core to your the
从一个核心 的控制 远
core that's accessing it do the lock
核心多数民众赞成访问它做锁
unlock and then it gets grabbed back for
解锁， 然后它被抓住回来
it so it's a miserable performance or
它所以这是一个悲惨的性能或
cache huge overhead for the semaphore
信号量缓存巨大的开销
activities and just really a bad thing
活动，只是 真的坏事
all around and so lesson one is
各地，这样的教训之一是
semaphores
信号灯
or mutexes are very expensive and if
或互斥是非常昂贵的，如果
you're trying to do low level
你正在试图做的低水平
parallelism you don't want fine-grained
并行你不想细粒度
locking at that level otherwise you're
在该级别锁定否则你
just completely sunk and so that's not
只是完全沉没 ，因此这不是
the way to do it I will go into it but
要做到这一点，我会进入，但
there's quite a bit of literature about
有大约相当多的 文献
what they call lock free synchronization
他们所谓的无锁同步
which is a way to avoid semaphores but
这是为了避免信号量的方式，但
get the effect and they wouldn't work in
得到的效果，他们不会在工作
this context either those just if you've
这种情况下无论是那些刚刚如果你已经
ever heard that term those are generally
听说过这个词的一般
designed for
设计
examples where you expect relatively
你想到哪里比较实例
little contention between the threads
线程之间的竞争不大
and so you try and be optimistic and
所以你尽量 保持乐观的态度
then roll back if something bad happens
然后回滚如果有什么不好的事情发生
this is a case where nope all those
这是一个情况下 都能跟得上所有这些
threads are going to be pounding that
线程将要 冲击的是
one memory location and they're really
一个内存位置 ，他们真的很
fighting for it and so there is no good
争取它，所以 没有什么好
solution to that problem the other thing
解决这一问题 的另一件事
I'll point out is this jump here shows
我要指出的是这一跳在这里 表演
you that hyper threading isn't really
你超线程是不是真的
helping us here going from the fact that
帮助我们在这里从一个事实，即去
we slow down from eight to sixteen means
我们从 8至16个手段 减缓
we can't really make use of sixteen
我们真的不能使用十六
threads in this application eight
在这种应用 八线程
threads are better than four but
线程是超过四个更好，但
obviously all that's kind of a waste of
显然一切有点浪费
time because this is just really a bad
时间，因为这 仅仅 是 一个真正的坏
idea all around so let's do something
想法各地 让我们做一些事情
different let's have each of them
不同让我们每个人
accumulate their own sum for their own
积累自己的总和为自己
sub range and we'll give up so we'll
子范围，我们就会放弃，所以我们会
have an array of accumulators where the
有蓄能器，其中的阵列
each thread is incrementing only a one
每个线程被递增只有一个
element of this array so they're not
这个数组的元素，以便他们不
fighting with each other directly for it
直接相互争抢它
but they are fighting for if you think
但他们都在争取 ，如果你认为
about it for the same cache line because
它为同一高速缓存行，因为
an array is typically stored and so it's
阵列通常被存储，因此它的
not totally nice but it gives you a
没有完全好，但 它给你一个
pointer to this idea if we could sort of
指针指向这个想法，如果我们可以 排序 的
move into a private state the stuff that
进入私人 状态的东西 ，
we're making the most direct access to
我们正在 以 最直接 的 访问
then we'll get better performance so
然后我们会得到更好的性能 等等
this is the thread routine and the point
这是常规线 和点
is that there's some global array called
是 ， 有一些所谓的全局数组
P some but it's only incrementing the
P一些，但它只是递增
the part of it that sort of assigned to
它的部分之类的分配
this particular thread and here you do
这个特殊的线程，在这里你做
see a performance improvement right so
看到性能改进权利，使
one thread takes five seconds remember
一个线程需要五秒的时间记
before it was 58 so that shows you just
这是 58前，使显示 的只是
the advantage of the cost of semaphores
信号灯的成本优势
right there is a factor of ten and you
在那里为10个 ，你的一个因素
see you are actually getting an
看到你实际得到 的
improvement all across the line
改善所有跨线
including up to 16 3
包括高达16 3
- still getting an improvement it would
-仍然得到改善 ，将
flatten out I should have shown the
拉平我应该所示
number 432 but it would flatten out at
号432，但它会在变平
this point but it actually is getting
这一点，但它实际上是越来越
some advantage out of hyper-threading as
一些优势了超线程作为
well so that's good it's not an amazing
舒服，所以这是很好的它不是 一个惊人
speed up so you can think of what they
加快使你能想到的他们
call the speed up is the performance of
调用速度提高了性能
it running on a single core versus the
它在单核与运行
performance on n cores and in the ideal
n个内核，并在理想的性能
case it goes n times faster and we're
情况下它会快N倍，我们很
not quite hitting that all but here's
不太击中所有，但这里的
you've already learned that it's
你已经了解到， 这是
generally bad to be accumulating into a
普遍不好被累积成
memory and so why not do the thing we
内存为什么不能做的事情，我们
learned before which is you accumulate
这是你积累以前学过
in a register and you only update the
在寄存器中，你只更新
memory when you're done with that so
当你与这样做内存
let's just do that and I'll call that
让我们只是做到这一点 ，我会打电话给那
the local version I'll just increment a
本地版本我就递增
sum which is a local variable and only
总和，其是一个局部变量和唯一
when I'm done then I'll store it in the
当我做我就会把它存储在
global array okay so it functionally
全局数组好了，所以它在功能上
equivalent to the one we just showed
相当于一个我们刚刚出现
we're just moving instead of
我们准备搬家，而不是
accumulating in a global array we're
积累在全球阵列我们
accumulating in a register and here you
累积在寄存器中，在这里你
see a pretty big performance improvement
看到一个相当大的性能提升
so blue is what we showed with the the
那么蓝就是我们显示出与该
global array red or orange is what's
全球阵 红色或橙色是什么
this local variable and so you see it's
这个局部变量，所以你看到它的
actually interesting we're getting a
实际上有趣我们得到一个
performance improvement as well although
性能改进以及虽然
it bottoms out at 8 and it actually gets
它在8见底，它实际上 得到
worse when you go to 16 and this is
更糟糕 ，当你到16，这 是
showing that hyper-threading isn't
示出 超线程不
really helping here because basically
真正帮助这里，因为基本上
the the single thread is just
在单线程只是
accumulating as fast as it can and
积累尽可能快，因为它可以和
adding to a register and so it's making
增加寄存器，因此它 使
pretty good use of what functional units
相当不错的使用什么功能单元
it uses and putting multiple threads
它使用并把多线程
sharing it isn't really helping at least
分享它不是真正帮助至少
not on the shark machines this actually
没有鲨鱼机这实际上
might be different on different machines
可能是在 不同的机器 不同
and actually if you recall from the
实际上，如果你从召回
performance optimization we found that
性能优化，我们发现，
if you're just doing a bunch of
如果你只是做了一堆
additions you can make use of the
添加你可以利用的
Scioscia tivity and get more
肖夏tivity并获得更多的
accumulation in parallel so you could
积累并行，所以你可以
actually speed up this program just the
实际上加快了这一计划 只是
single threaded version of this program
这个程序的单线程版本
pretty well but anyways it shows that
非常好，但不管怎么说它表明，
okay this is starting to look like your
好吧，这是开始 看起来 像你的
your a your single threaded performance
你的一个你的单线程性能
is pretty good and B you're getting some
是相当不错的和B你得到一些
useful speed up out of parallelism but
有用加快了并行， 但
as I said this is like the easiest
正如我所说，这是像 最简单 的
example in the world to parallel life so
例如，在世界 平行的生活如此
if you can't do it here then then life
如果你不能做到这一点这里，那么当时的生活
is pretty hopeless as far as
很绝望，只要
multi-threading so let's talk about as I
多线程所以让我们来谈谈，因为我
mentioned this idea of speed-up so
提到这个想法的 加速使
speed-up is just defined to be the time
加速只是定义为时间
for a single-threaded program divided by
对于一个单线程程序 除以
the time for 4 P threads running or
为4个P线程时运行 或
actually will use it P cores instead of
居然会用它P 芯代替
P threads question yes generally the
P个线程问题是一般
scheduler has some kind of go dancing
调度有某种 去 跳舞 的
built into it and it will tend to
内置到它，它会倾向于
especially in a case like this where the
尤其是在这样的情况 下
threads are sort of grabbing and running
线程排序的抓取和运行
making they will generally get spread
使得他们通常会 得到传播
across the course so that's a pretty the
在整个过程中所以 这是一个相当的
Linux scheduler is pretty good at that
Linux调度是 在那个 不错
when you have more threads than there
当你有比有更多的线程
are cores then then it basically starts
是核心，然后再就基本开始
scheduling them in some cyclic order and
在一些循环顺序安排他们和
you won't you'll at best you will not
你不会，你会在最好的，你不会
get any advantage and in the worst case
获得任何优势，在最坏的情况下，
you actually start slowing down from
你真正开始从放缓
having more threads than are there good
具有比多线程有很好的
question so there's really two versions
问题所以没什么两个版本
of speed-up one is if I take my
的加速一个是，如果我把我的
multi-threaded routine and run it with
多线程的程序，并运行它
one thread and then I met do with P
一个线程，然后我遇到了这样做的P
threads or cores I can get a speed-up
线程或内核 ，我可以得到一个 加速
but actually the truer thing is if I
但实际上更真实的 事情是，如果我
take the best-known
拿最知名的
sequential algorithm for performing this
递推算法 执行此
task with the best implementation of
任务与最佳实施
that and then I compared against my
这一点 ，然后我对我的比较
parallel one so that's referred to as
并联的一个所以这被称为
absolute speed up which is that the best
绝对加速这是最好的
measures you know you give both sides
测量你知道你给双方
the opportunity to do the best
机会做最好
implementation that they can and then
实施，他们可以再
you compare it and then what's referred
你比较一下，然后什么简称
to as the efficiency is how close to the
为效率是如何接近
speed-up get to the ideal speed-up which
加速 获得理想的加速，其
is if I'm running on P cores
是，如果我P上内核上运行
I should be P times faster and you'll
我应该为P倍的速度，你会
see that we're you know the question of
看到我们，你 知道的问题
hyper-threading versus not we're sort of
超线程与没有 我们那种
here we're saying no you don't we're not
这里我们要说不，你不我们不
trying to gain from hyper-threading you
试图从获得超线程 你
can play this game various ways and you
可以玩这个游戏的各种方式和你
can argue back and forth whether
可以说来回是否
hyper-threading should count so for P is
超线程应该算作所以P 是
P the total number of possible threads
P可能的线程的总数
or the total number of cores that's
或 核心的总数是
really something to argue back and forth
真的东西 扯皮
about so the point is the efficiency
关于这样的点是效率
though is measured as how much do we do
虽然是衡量有多少，我们做
relative to ideal and so this is what
相对于理想的，因此这是什么
you get for this code the local version
你得到这个代码的本地版本
of P some you'll see that our efficiency
P的部分，你会看到我们的效率
numbers are somewhere in the high
数字是在 高某处
somebody range which is good but not
这是很好的，但不会有人范围
great it's pretty good actually if you
大这是相当不错实际上，如果你
can get 75% efficiency you're doing
可以得到 75％ 的效率，你正在做的
better than most but again that's
最 要好 ，但再次这
because this should have been the
因为这本来应该是
world's easiest program to parallelize
世界上最简单的程序并行
so and the best speed-up we're getting
所以，最好的加速我们得到
is a factor of six out of eight cores so
是六出于八个 核心的因素等等
again that's pretty good but this really
再次就不错了，但是这真的
should be something you can do well so
应该是你可以 做的这么好
that just gives you a flavor of what
只是给你一个什么样的味道
parallel computing can be so now it's
并行计算可以是这样，现在是
sort of back off and talk some general
有点背过，聊一些一般
principle just like the speed-up there's
原理就像加速有
a tonne of genome Dahl who
基因组 达尔 的每吨 谁
coincidentally just died a few weeks ago
巧合的是刚刚去世几个星期前
you might have seen it in the news he
你 可能会在 新闻 中已经看到了 他
was one of the original pioneers at IBM
在IBM原有的先驱者之一
in
在
their mainframe computers then then at
他们的大型计算机，然后再在
some point he in the 60s he started his
某些时候，他在60年代，他开始了他
own company called um dal computers and
自己的公司称为庵 DAL电脑
they were like they were the the cool
他们就像他们是凉爽
company in mainframe computers if that
公司在大型计算机如果
could ever be considered cool right and
能否 被认为是凉爽 的权利 和
he built a competitor's to IBM that
他 建立了一个 竞争对手对 IBM说
absolutely drove them crazy because they
绝对驱使他们疯狂，因为他们
had a virtual monopoly they actually
有一个虚拟的垄断，他们实际上
were subject to the antitrust suit so um
是受到反垄断诉讼所以， 嗯
Dahl was a suit of the the rebel who
达尔 是反叛的西装谁
broke away from the mother company and
从母公司打破了并且
started a competitor and he made this
开始一个竞争对手，他做出这个
very simple observation that's called
很简单的观察这就是所谓的
Amdahl's law which is basically junior
Amdahl定律基本上是初中
high level algebra to think of this but
高水平代数想到这一点 ，但
it's actually a fairly perceptive point
它实际上是一个相当敏锐的点
about what's the possible benefit of
关于什么是可能的好处
speeding up something and this is
加快东西，这 是
discussed in the book you know this
你知道这 本书讨论
isn't just for computers it's any
不仅仅是电脑它的任何
process that you want to speed up and
要加快进程，
it's very simple observations which is
这是非常简单的 观察是
supposed to some fraction of a system
据说在 系统的 某些部分
that I can make go faster and I'll call
我可以走得更快， 我会打电话给
that fraction P P is some number between
那部分是PP 之间的 一些数
zero and one point zero right 100% zero
零和一点 零权 100％ 的零
percent and let's suppose we take that
％，而假设我们采取
part that we're going to make run faster
我们打算让运行速度更快的一部分
and improve its performance by a factor
并能由因子提高其性能
okay then we can just very simply talk
好吧，那么我们就可以非常 简单谈
about what will be the benefit of that
什么将成为该利益
performance so we'll call it T sub K and
性能，所以我们就叫它 透射次K和
what it says is the fraction P of the
它说什么是对的p部分
time will be reduced by K but the
时间会被K，但可以减少
fraction that you can't change a one
分数，你不能改变 一个
minus P will remain at its old time and
减去P将保留其旧时代和
that I'm dolls law that's it that's the
我是娃娃 的法律就是这样这就是
whole thing and one interesting measure
整个事情，一个有趣的措施
is what if K were infinity what if we
是什么，如果K含量无穷大，如果我们什么
had unbounded resources to speed things
有无限的资源，以提高办事效率
up and what the observation is the best
起来，什么观察是最好的
speed up you'll get is a 1 minus P and
加快你将得到的是1个减去P 和
so just think it this way if you have
所以才觉得它这样，如果你有
ten percent of it that
它的百分之十是
can't change the other 90% you make
无法改变对方90％你做
infinitely fast then your performance
无限快那么你的表现
improvement will be a factor of 10
改善将是10倍
that's really all it's a pretty
这真的这是一个非常
straightforward idea so this has sort of
简单的想法所以这有几分
direct implications in so the example is
在这样的例子是有直接影响
suppose that we can improve the
假设我们可以提高
performance of some system of 90% of it
的是 90％ 的人受到系统的性能
and we can speed up by factor 9 and that
我们可以通过因子9和加快
number is chosen to make the numbers
选择号码 进行号码
work out then we'll get it best at 2x
工作了，然后我们会 在2个 最好把它
performance improvement basically what
性能的提高基本上是什么
it says is the part of the system that
它说的 是 系统 的一部分
you can't speed up will become your
你不能加快将成为你的
bottleneck and that's just the way it is
瓶颈，这只是事情是这样的
so the implication to this repair while
所以蕴涵这个维修而
programming are fairly obvious that if
编程是相当明显 ，如果
we can take our application and chop off
我们可以把我们的应用程序，并砍掉
some fraction of it and make it run K
它的某些部分，使 之一连串k
times faster by running it on K cores
倍的速度由日K内核上运行它
then
然后
the part of it that still running
它的一部分 仍在运行
sequentially will come to will limit the
依次将前来将限制
ultimate performance we can get so
极致的性能，我们可以得到这样
that's not really an issue for this
这不是真正为 这个 问题
summation problem because it really does
求和问题，因为它确实
divide into as many independent tasks as
分成许多独立的任务
you have numbers and as you can see you
你有一个数字，正如你可以 看到你
can make them run but many other
可以让他们运行，但许多其他
applications do some part of it that I
应用程序做它的某些部分，我
can't really make no parallel so just as
真的不能没有平行，就像
an example and just for the sake of this
一个例子，只是为了这个缘故
class you know an example of a little
类，你知道 一点的例子
bit more involved a problem in parallel
位更 涉及并行 的 问题
programming and multi-threading let's
编程和多线程咱们
think about sorting a bunch of numbers
想想分拣一堆数字
so we have n numbers and we want to sort
所以我们有n个数，我们想排序
them and we have some number of threads
他们和我们有线程的一些数
that we can do this with is there way we
我们能做到这与有没有办法，我们
can speed this up and you think about it
可以加快这和你想想看
not that clear how you do it there's
不说清楚，你是怎么做到的有
actually a vast literature in parallel
实际上是一个大量文献中并行
sorting and those you've taken or will
排序和那些你已经采取 或将
take the class to town will be exposed
走班 镇将被暴露
to all of this but I'm just going to do
所有这一切，但 我 只是 打算 做
a very simple version which is quicksort
一个很简单的版本，这是快速排序
so quick SART is for example the the C
这么快SART是例如 与 c
library program Q sort is quicksort it
库程序 ●排序是快速排序 它
was invented in the early 1960s or 1950s
在 20世纪60年代初50年代或者被发明
by a guy named Tony Hoare who also
由一位名叫托尼·霍雷谁也家伙
founded a lot of the fundamental logic
创立了很多 基本 的 逻辑
of program so he's like an amazing
程序 ， 所以他就像一个 惊人
person still alive today lives in
人还活着，今天 生活在
Cambridge England but if you ever have a
剑桥英格兰，但如果你曾经有一个
chance to go to talk by him do so he's
机会去 由他 来 谈谈 这样做的他
an amazing person anyways the idea
一个了不起的人，反正这个想法
quicksort is very simple and this is
快速排序是非常简单的，这 是
sort of the basic sorting algorithm you
排序的基本排序算法的你
grab some element from the array that
抓住从所述阵列的一些元件，其
you're trying to sort and that's called
你想 进行排序和这就是所谓的
the pivot and then you split the data so
枢轴 ， 然后拆分数据，以便
that you look at the elements that are
你看看那些元素
either greater or less than the pivot
比枢轴或者更大或更小
and potentially also equal let's just
并有可能也等于让我们只
assume all the elements are unique here
假设所有的元素是唯一在这里
so you just split it into two of piles
所以你只要 把它分成两堆
one is the lesson once a greater now you
一个是曾经的教训更大的现在你
creatively you recursively you sort
创造性你递归 您 排序
those two piles by the same method and
这两个桩通过相同的方法 和
when it's all done you end up with
当这一切都 完成你结束了
everything sorted one nice thing about
一切都整理 约 一个很好的 事
it is it can be done in place meaning if
这是它 可 代替的意思，如果完成
you have an array of data you can do
你有你可以做一组数据
this all just by swapping elements
这一切只需通过交换元素
around and not have to use any extra
围而不需要使用任何额外的
space which you would for example with
空间， 你会例如 用
merge sort so this is a fairly simple
归并排序，所以这是一个相当简单的
algorithm and just to visualize it then
算法，只是对其进行可视化，然后
you have some block of data X array and
你有数据X阵列的一些块
you want to sort it so you pick an
要排序，所以你挑
element called the pivot and there's
元素被称为支点 和有
various strategies for doing that and
做这件事的各种策略和
now you just subdivide X into three
现在你只细分X为三
parts L the left hand R the right hand
份L- 左手 R是右手
meaning less and greater than P and then
这意味着比P，然后更少和更大的
you place P in the middle and then you
你所P在中间，然后你
recursively when you're doing this for
递归当你这样做的
in a sequential code you'll pick one of
在连续的代码，你会挑一个
these two usually leftmost or rightmost
这两种通常最左侧或最
whatever doesn't really matter and
什么其实并不重要，并
you'll recursively you apply the same
你会递归地应用相同
method to to the left side in
方法向左侧
ultimately after enough recursions you
最终经过足够递归的
get to the point where el has been
得到的地方 ，EL已经 点
sorted and that's shown in this kind of
排序，这是一个 在这种 所示
a swishy color thing and call that L
一个swishy色彩的事情，并呼吁使L
Prime and same with
总理与同
you'll do the same thing now with the
你现在会做同样的事情与
right hand side and when you're done
右手边，当你完成
this is usually done in place so you're
这 通常是在地方这样做 你
just the L part works on one array
只是将L部分工作在一个 阵列 上
part of the array and our card on
该阵列的一部分，我们 的卡
another and when you're done they're in
另外，当你完成他们在
sorted order so very simple sort and
有序所以很简单的排序和
generally has very good performance so
一般具有 很好的性能 ，以便
this is what the code for it looks like
这就是它的代码看起来像
which is usually you have is a special
这通常是你必须是一个特殊的
case if there's only one or two elements
情况下，如果只有一个或两个 元素
and then you do this partitioning so
然后你做这种划分使
this routine of splitting it between the
之间拆分它的 这个程序
left and the right-hand part is handled
左， 右侧部分被处理
by a function called partition and then
由函数调用分区，然后
if there's more than one element in the
如果有一个以上的 元素是在
left side you sort that and if there's
左侧你那种，如果有
more than one element in the right-hand
在右手 多于 一个的元件
side you sort that and then when all
侧你那种，然后当所有
these recursions are done then the array
这些递归完成则数组
is sorted so pretty typical code and we
排序所以非常典型的代码，我们
won't go in the trickiest part writing
不会在最棘手的部分写入走
the code is how do you make this
代码是你如何使这个
partitioning go fast but I won't go into
分区走 的快，但我不会去
that just imagine it happens so this
只是 想象它发生所以这
algorithm actually has a natural version
实际的算法具有天然的版本
of parallelism which is in my sequential
并行这是在我的顺序
version I was sorting both first the
版本我第一次排序都
left and then the left of the left and
左边，然后在左侧的左侧和
the left of the left of the left and
左边 的 左边的左边和
kind of working my way until I got that
样 的工作我的方式，直到我得到 的
whole array sorted and then I was coming
整个数组排序，然后我来了
back and I was working on the right and
背部和我工作的权利，
then the left part of the right and the
然后右侧 和 左侧 部分
left to the left to the right and blah
左向左向右 和嗒嗒
blah blah and doing these recursions
等等等等，做这些递归
because the way the codes written right
因为这样的代码编写权
I am doing the full sort of the
我做了充分的排序的
left-hand part and only after that is
左手部分后，才 为
sorted then I'm doing the complete sort
排序然后我做的完全排序
of the right-hand part so the point is
右手部分的故点
it's it's an algorithm where I'm working
这是它在那里我工作的算法
just on one part of the array at a time
只是在时间的阵列中的一个部分
but there's a very natural recursion of
但有一个 很自然的递归
parallelism here that says okay I've got
并行这里 ，说好吧，我已经有了
two parts each beat need to be sorted
两个部分 每个节拍需要 进行排序
let me just fire off two threads and let
让我火了两个线程，让
them deal with that and that's the so
他们处理这个，这就是所谓
it's what you call divide and conquer
这是你所说的分而治之
parallelism it
它的并行
a natural kind of parallelism it shows
一个自然的一种并行它显示
up in this code so basically I'll do the
在这片代码所以基本上我会做
same thing as before all at the top
同样的事情，之前的所有顶部
level will be a purely sequential
水平将 是一个纯粹的顺序
process of partitioning and but then
分区和，但过程则
assuming the partition comes up with
假设磁盘分区来了
some non-trivial split then I will
一些不平凡的拆分，然后我会
recursively begin fork off to threads
递归开始叉关闭以螺纹
each of which will be responsible for
其中 的每 一个将负责
the other and so we'll sort of look like
其他以此类推，我们会有点像
I'm working on the two parts in parallel
我工作 的两个部分并行
and eventually both sides will end up
最终双方将结束
now this picture isn't really quite true
现在这幅画是不是真的完全正确
and that it looked makes it look like
并且，它期待使它看起来像
they're all kind of synchronized
他们都是那种同步
together and I'm doing you know
一起和我做的，你知道
KABOOOM down like this in a strict way
KABOOOM下来这样一个严格的方法
but in fact they're not it's very
但其实他们不是 很
asynchronous the left part is one thread
异步的左侧部分是一个螺纹
the right is another they just go at
右边是另一个他们只是在去
their own pace and at the end I'm just
自己的节奏，并在年底，我只是
going to wait for it all to complete but
要 等到这 一切 完成，但
there's no strict temporal ordering on
没有严格的时间顺序上
how that all occurs
怎么说都发生
so the way I'll write this in the code
这样的方式，我会在代码中写
is available on the courts website I'm
可在 法院网站我 在
only going to show you a glimpse of it
只是要告诉 你它的一瞥
it's a non-trivial amount of code it
它的代码不平凡的量就
takes to do it but basically what I'm
需要做， 但我基本上什么
going to do is have a bunch of pool of
要做的是有一堆池
threads that are ready to work and
线程准备工作，
that's a pretty typical way you write
这就是你写一个非常典型的方式
threaded code because actually the the
线程代码，因为实际上的
initiation of a thread is a non-trivial
一个线程的启动是一个不平凡
amount of computation so usually what
计算量所以 平时什么
you do is you say I've got this many
你要做的就是你说我有这么多
cores I'm going to create a set of that
核心我要创建 一组
many threads and they will each work by
许多线程，他们将分别由工作
sharing a task queue so some agent that
共享任务队列所以有些剂
is forking off work for the different
是分叉关闭工作，为不同
threads to do they will do the work
线程做自己会做的工作
assigned to them when that complete
分配给他们当完成
we'll come back and say okay I'm ready
我们会回来 ，说好吧，我已经准备好了
for something new and it will give them
新的东西，它会给他们
something new so I there's a little bit
新的东西，所以我有一点点
of code a very rudimentary code there of
代码非常基本的 代码存在的
creating this task model and task
创建该任务模型和任务
adjoint so the basic rule will be any
伴随 这样的基本规则会有什么
given task any given thread then at any
给定的任务任何给定的线程，然后在任何
given time has been assigned sub sub
给定的时间已分配子子
range of this array to be a sorting and
此数组的范围是 一个排序和
it will be specified by the base meaning
它将由基 含义来指定
the starting point of this particular
这个特殊的出发点
range and then the number of elements
范围，然后将元件的数
that it's told it's sort and one other
， 它的告诉它的排序和另一
thing I'll do is once I get down to this
我会做的事情是，一旦我得到了这个
array being small enough I'll just sort
阵列足够小我就排序
it sequentially and and we'll see how
它依次，我们将看到如何
big that block is or not is actually
大该块是与否实际上是
performance parameter that you can use
您可以使用性能参数
for tuning the program so the point is
用于调谐程序，以便点是
that you don't want to take this down
你不想 借此下来
too far because the sort of overhead of
太远，因为那种 开销
threads is enough that when you get to
线程是足够的，当你 到
fine-grained you're actually going to
细粒度你居然要去
start losing performance
开始失去性能
so assume that it's bigger than that
因此认为它比这更大
I've been given some block there what
我一直在考虑一些块有什么
I'll do then is I'll run the partition
我会做的就是，我会运行分区
step this thread will run it a
这一步线程将运行它
partitioned step just using the exact
只是用精确分割步
function I showed you or didn't show you
功能我发现你还是没有告诉你
and then as long as and then I will us
然后只要然后我会为我们
create and add to the task queue two new
创建并添加到任务队列 两个新
tasks a one dhis for the left part and
任务 一个 dhis的左半部分和
one for the right part and then the
一个正确的部分，然后
scheduler that will assign two threads
调度程序将分配两个线程
to handle those two parts and so that
处理这些两个 部分，使
code will that's exactly how the code is
代码会 是这样的代码究竟如何是
going to work it's going to keep reusing
上班这将继续重用
the same threads over and over again too
一遍又一遍的过同一主题
but at any given time they'll be given a
但在任何给定的时间，他们会 得到一个
range of places what typically will
地方范围是什么一般
happen is they'll run their partitioning
发生在他们会运行他们的分区
step and then say okay I've done my job
步骤，然后说，好吧，我已经做了 我的工作
now assigned to new to new threads to do
现在分配到新的新的线程做
this and that's the general scheme of it
这一点，这是它的总体方案
or they'll say this is a small enough
或者他们会说这 是足够小
block I'm just going to sort the darn
块我只是要 排序 的混账
thing okay so that's really all the code
好了，这样的事情真的所有的代码
does it's online if you're interested in
确实是在网上，如果你有兴趣
this kind of stuff it's I think it's
这种东西是 我认为这是
pretty well written code because I wrote
不错编写的代码，因为我写的
it
它
so this is sort of the somewhat
所以这是那种有点
simplified version of the code say
代码的简化版本说
initialize my task queue scheduling
初始化我的任务队列调度
system create global variables of
系统创建的全局变量
describing the beginning and end of this
描述此开始和结束
array to be sorted create a new task
要排序的数组创建新任务
queue and then this is the main function
队列，然后这是主要的功能
that the TQ sort helper is given some
该TQ排序助手给出一些
range of of addresses and a pointer to
的地址范围的指针和指向
the task queue that fuse to manage these
该 融合管理这些任务队列
tasks and then when it's all done it
任务，然后当这一切都做到了
will just wait till all the tasks have
只会等到所有的任务都有
completed this is the top level this
完成这 是顶层这
isn't part of any recursion this is the
没有任何递归的一部分，这是
top level code and then it will free up
顶级的代码，然后它会释放
the data structures and then this is the
的数据结构，然后，这 是
part of it that actually does the real
它的一部分，实际上 确实实
work it will say so now the TQ sort
工作会这么说，现在的TQ排序
helper is the part that's assigned to to
助手是已分配给该部分
sort some particulars from the starting
从开始的一些细节进行排序
address the base and some number of
解决碱和一定数目的
elements and so this is what each task
元素和所以这是每个任务
will do and it says ok if this is a
会做，它说 好 ，如果这是一个
small enough block of elements I'm just
元素足够小的块我只是
going to call my serial quicksort to do
要叫我的串行快速排序做
it otherwise I'm going to
它否则我要去
oh it's a little bit messier than this
哦，这是一个 有点 混乱比 这
okay now otherwise it's going to spawn a
现在没事了，否则它会酿出
task to do the sorting let's see I was a
任务做排序，让我们看看我是 一个
little mixed up this is a high level so
有点混了，这是一个很高的水平，从而
the actual splitting occurs in this
实际的分裂发生在这个
thing which is where it's so this is the
这就是事情的地方是如此，这 是
actual thread routine and what it's
实际线程程序以及它的
saying is run the partition here and
说是这里运行分区和
then call this TQ sort helper which you
然后把这个TQ排序帮助您
just saw on the left and the right parts
刚才看到的左边和右边部分
of it so just to review then the actual
它所以只是审查则实际
spawning of a task is done by this
任务的产卵被 这个 工作
helper routine but then that what it
辅助函数，但是那么是什么
calls is the the thread routine is what
调用是线程程序是什么
does the work here and what it will do
这里做的工作以及它会做
is it will do the partitioning within
是它会做内部的分区
that thread and then it will just throw
该线程然后它会随便扔
back and add to the task you two calls
背部和添加到任务 你 两个电话
to this helper but as that kind of so
这个帮手，但作为一种如此
between these two routines you can see
这两个程序之间可以看到
it's doing this idea of divide and
它做的这个想法鸿沟和
conquer parallelism so this is a
征服并行 所以这 是一个
performance running on the shark machine
鲨鱼机上运行的性能
and this is a fairly straightforward I'm
这是一个相当简单的我
just taking some number of random value
只是把随机值的一定数目
two to this 37th
两本37
that can't be right this is numbers not
这不可能是正确的 ，这是 不是 数字
to the thirty-seventh right you agree
你同意 第三十七权
with me 237th is 128 billion roughly so
我237是128个十亿大致如此
this number is not right I'll have to
这个数字是不正确的，我会要
check it out and now what this x axis so
检查出来，现在这是什么x轴 这样
the y axis just denotes how long does it
y轴表示只是需要多长时间
take to complete by the way one thing if
采取的方式有一两件事，如果完成
you're used to measuring performance
你已经习惯了 性能 测试
based on CPU time that's not useful when
基于CPU的时间，这不是有用的时
you're talking a parallel computing you
你说一个并行计算你
really want to talk a elapsed time the
真的想谈一个经过的时间
time that you get from looking at a
时间， 你 从寻找一个 获得
clock and measuring it and dealing with
时钟和测量，并处理
whatever inefficiency occurs there so
无论出现效率低下，从而有
these are actually the last runtime of
这些实际上的最后运行时间
the entire program and you'll see that
整个程序，你会看到，
it varies according to this thing called
它根据这个东西叫做变化
the serial fraction the serial fraction
串行分数串行分数
is just at what point do I slide between
只是在我 之间滑动 点什么
a serial quicksort or keep dividing so
串行快速排序或保持分裂等等
how big does the array need to be as a
有多大请问阵列需要像一个
fraction expressed as a fraction of the
分数表示为的一小部分
original array before I I will go into
原来前阵II将进入
recursion if I were actually to write
递归如果我确实 写
this real application I wouldn't do it
这个实际应用中，我不会做
based on a fraction I'd do it based on a
根据分数我会做它基于一个
block size to say anything smaller than
块大小说什么小于
a thousand elements or some number like
一千元素或一些数字， 如
that but this code just happens to be
该但是这个代码恰好是
expressed this way but the thing to
这种方式表达，但事
notice that's interesting is you'll see
请注意，有趣的是，你会看到
here if the fraction is 1
此处若分数为1
it basically says I won't split this at
它基本上是说我不会在这个分裂
all I'm just going to call a sequential
所有我只是要调用顺序
quicksort so this is a purely sequential
快速排序，所以这是一个纯粹的顺序
version of it and what it shows is if I
它的版本，它显示 的是，如果 我
once I start - I'll be willing to sort
一旦我开始-我会愿意排序
of split this up and do parallelism I
分裂的这件事，做我的并行
start making it run faster and faster
开始使它越跑越快
and faster I'll and then I get into this
和更快的我会，然后我进入这个
trough and now if I start going finer
触底 ，现在如果我开始去细
and finer grained then I'm running into
和细粒度然后我运行到
the problem where the thread overhead is
当线程开销问题
more than the advantage I'm getting by
以上优势，我通过获取
doing the parallelism
做并行
and I'm faster to run that bought big
而且我更快地运行 大 买
assort just using a sequential algorithm
配全只是使用顺序算法
rather than parallel but the good news
而不是平行的，但好 消息
here is this is a pretty long trough
这里，这是一个相当长的槽
here so it means that if you're trying
这里，所以这意味着，如果你 想
to tune this program it's not that hard
调整这一计划也并不难
you're not going to pay a huge penalty
你不打算 支付巨额罚款
if you don't know a parameter exactly so
如果你不知道确切的参数等等
as long as because this is a huge range
只要是因为这是 一个巨大的 范围
right 30 from a 32 to 4096 it's a factor
从32到4096右30 这是一个因素
of of a lot to the fifth and due to the
的很多的第五和因
twelfth since two to the seventh sector
由于 两个 12世纪 到第七分区
128 see how I do my arithmetic in powers
128看我怎么做我的算术权力
of two anyways it's roughly at you know
两个 反正它大致在你知道
128 so several orders of magnitude
128个这样几个订单
decimal orders of magnitude over which
幅度的十进制订单超过其
you get pretty comparable performance so
你得到相当相当的性能，所以
that means from a performance tuning
从一个性能调整装置
point of view it's not that hard to do
的角度来看，这并不难做到
and you'll often see we're getting a
你会经常看到我们得到 一个
pretty decent speed up on our eight core
我们的八大核心相当不错的加速
to a hyper-threaded machine we're
到超线程机器我们
getting basically a 7x performance and
越来越基本上是7倍的性能和
hyper-threading really isn't helping us
超线程真的不帮助 我们
at all is part of the lesson here but if
在所有为 课程 的一部分， 在这里，但如果
you just think of it as a course and
你只是把它作为一门课程和
that's pretty good
就不错了
so there is an obvious place here where
所以有一个明显的地方在这儿，
there's a Nam Dolls law issue going on
那里将 在 南 娃娃法律问题
if you think at that first top-level
如果你想的 第一个 顶级
split the first call to partition is
分割所述 第一呼叫到 分区是
being done over the entire array by a
通过整个阵列上正在做
serial sequential process right so at
串行顺序处理的权利 因此在
the very least that is not going
最起码 是不会
parallel at all there's going exactly
并行在所有那里将 准确
one thread is doing the initial
一个线程是做初始
partition and then that splits into two
分区，然后该分裂成两个
so at most you have two threads where
所以最多有两个线程，其中
it's a parallelism and then the next
这是一个并行 再下
level down at most four and so you
级下调最多四等你
really don't you have to get several
真的没有，你必须得到几个
levels of recursion down before you're
递归级别 下跌你之前
really running on all the course that
所有课程真正运行
you have available so you'd think that
你们有 那么你会认为
that's limiting your speed up and it
是的限制条件，加快 并
does and that's part of the reason why
的确， 这就是的原因部分
our best performance is a factor of
我们最好的表现 是一个因素
seven and not a factor of eight or more
七不是8倍以上
so there's quite a bit of work as I
所以有相当多的工作，因为我
mentioned on how to speed up performance
就如何加快性能提到
including how to make quicksort go
包括如何使快速排序去
faster so there's a vast body of
快所以有一个庞大的机构
literature on parallel stories
文献上平行的故事
so one thing I tried was to say okay
这么一两件事我想是 说 好了
well let's try and do this partitioning
那么让我们来尝试做这种划分
step that week the top couple levels
步骤当周最热门的几个 级别
let's try and do a parallel version of
让我们尝试做的并行 版本
that and so the idea is you pick one
这一点，这样的想法是你一个挑
pivot element but now you fire in this
主元，但现在你在这个火
example for threads and each of those
例如用于螺纹和各那些的
four threads runs a partition step on on
四个线程运行的分区步骤对
1/4 of the range and it will generate
该范围的1/4，它会 产生
their own versions of left and right and
自己的左侧和右侧版本和
then you globally figure out how many
那么全球弄清楚有多少
are in each of these sub ranges and then
在每个这些子范围，然后的
you tell each thread okay now you copy
你告诉每个线程现在没事了，你复制
your part of it over to the relevant
你的一部分移交给相关
section of the array but the good news
该阵列的部分，但好消息
so there's some amount of
所以有一定量
synchronization that goes on there but
同步是继续存在，但
you can imagine that this partitioning
你能想象 ，这个分区
step once when you're running it is
当你运行 它是 一次一步
completely independent of across the
完全独立于整个的
different threads so it's getting a
不同的 线程所以它才获得了
almost ideal speed-up so I implemented
近乎理想的 速度， 所以我实现
this and tried and I couldn't make it
这一点，并试图和我不能 使它
run faster than the original code and I
运行比原来的代码，我快
think the the problem with this was the
认为这个 问题 是
copying the cost of copying data here
这里复制的复制数据的成本
was even though it's being done by
是，即使它被完成
multiple threads and getting pretty good
多线程 并获得不错
performance out of the memory system
表现出来的存储系统
because you're doing sequential copying
因为你正在做的连续复印
all the cash issues are pretty good here
所有的现金问题都 还不错这里
but that's just enough extra work that
但是这只是足够的 额外的工作 ，
has to be done for this parallel code
已经为 这个并行代码来完成
that doesn't have to be done the
在没有做的
sequential code is totally in place
顺序代码是完全到位
meaning not using any additional storage
意思是不使用任何额外的存储空间
not copying and so that's just enough of
不是抄袭等，这只是够
a penalty on the parallel part that it
上平行部，它是一个点球
didn't really improve performance at all
并没有真正改善性能在所有
so that code is shown as part of the
使得代码被示为 部分
code on the course website but like I
课程网站 ， 但就像我的代码
said I I banged on it quite a bit and
我说我撞了它 颇有 几分
tried to tune it and squeak it in
试图调整它，并发出吱吱它
various ways and could never make it so
各种途径和 从来不会这么
I got better overall performance
我得到了更好的整体性能
out of this program and so that's again
这一计划的，因此这是一次
a lesson and that's one of the
一个教训，这就是的一个
unfortunate lessons is you can spend a
不幸的教训是，你可以花
lot of time trying to make a program run
很多时间试图 使 程序运行
faster and get absolutely nowhere and
更快获得绝对行不通的，并
it's frustrating because you put in a
这是令人沮丧，因为你把一个
lot of work and you know it's a pretty
大量的工作，你知道这是一个非常
cool idea and you'd love to publish a
很酷的想法 ，你很乐意发布
paper about it or tell your friends
关于它的纸或者告诉 你的朋友
about it and it just goes nowhere and it
关于它， 它只是 无处它
just sits there and there's nothing
只是坐在那里并没有什么
unfortunately there's not an accumulated
不幸的是有没有一个累积
repository of the bad ideas of computer
计算机的 坏 主意库
science don't waste your time trying
科学不要浪费你的时间尝试
this that people can talk about so this
这一点，人们可以谈论所以这
is just a lesson to learn so anyways
只是 需要学习，反正 一 课
that was my experience with that again
那是 我与经验 再次
other people spend a lot more time this
别人花更多的时间这
is one of the most common applications
是最 常见的应用 之一
that people try to do parallel
人们试图做 并行
programming for so some of the lessons
编程所以一些经验
from this is you need a good strategy
从这个是你需要一个很好的策略
for how you're going to get parallelism
如何你会得到并行
out of your application and I showed you
您的应用程序，并且我发现你
two basic versions one is partitioned
两个基本版本的一个划分
into K parts they're more or less
为K他们或多或少
completely independent of each other or
完全相互独立的 或
something like a divide and conquer
有点 像分而 治之
strategy where you can keep splitting it
策略， 其中 你可以保持 它拆分
but the two splits that you create out
但两个裂口 您创建了
of that can go concurrently these other
那可以去这些并发其他
different types of parallelism too in
不同类型的并行 太
general you want to make the inner loops
一般要进行内部循环
you can't have any synchronization
你不能有任何 同步
primitives in there it'll just run too
原语有 它只会跑太
slow I'm dolls law as I mentioned is
慢我的玩偶法律正如我所提到的
always sort of lurking in the background
总是那种潜伏 在后台
of if you can only feed up a part of
如果你只能养活的一部分
your program then the other part will
你的程序那么另一部分
become the bottleneck but the other
成为瓶颈，但其他
thing is like I said you can do it
就是像我说你可以做到这一点
you've got the tools you've learned with
你有你有学习的工具
with P threads and your knowledge of
以P线程和你 的知识
programming and your understanding of
编程和你 的 理解
cache memories and things like that
高速缓存存储器之类 的 东西
you've got the tools you need to be an
你有你 需要的 工具
effective programmer of this kind
这种 有效的程序员
say but you have to and there's nothing
说不过你 得并没有什么
that beats sort of trial and error and
那跳动的排序试 错和
testing and tuning experimenting if
测试和调整，如果试验
there's some parameters that need to be
有需要一些参数
set then you want to run experiments
设置，则 您要运行 实验
that will sweep through the parameters
这将 通过参数 扫
to try and figure out what the settings
试图找出的设置
should be so that's sort of a little bit
应当所以 这是 那种 一点点
about parallel programming let me just
有关并行编程让我
finish this lecture with a little bit of
完成本次讲座 有一点点
sort of classic issues about concurrency
那种关于并发的经典问题
that that are critical when you're
当 你这个是关键
dealing with these systems based on what
处理 依据是什么，这些系统
you call a shared memory model of
你调用的共享存储器模型
computation so multi-core is an example
计算如此多核心是一个例子
of conceptually multi-threaded
的概念性多线程
computation remember you're you're
计算记住你是你
working within a single virtual address
单个虚拟地址内工作
space and you have private stacks but
空间，您有私人书库但
the more global the heap memory is
越是世界的堆内存
completely shared across threads and so
跨线程等完全共享
that what you call the shared memory
这就是你所谓的共享内存
programming model and that's what we've
编程模型，而这正是我们所
really been looking at in this course so
在这个过程中确实一直在 寻找这样
there's a certain interesting question
有一定的 有趣的问题
about called memory consistency models
关于所谓的内存一致性 模型
and here I'll illustrate it with a very
在这里我会很说明吧
simple example imagine we have two
简单的例子， 假设我们有 两个
global variables a and B and we have two
全局变量 a和b， 我们有 两个
different threads and so the first
不同线程 因此第一
thread is going to write meaning assign
线程会写含义分配
a value to a and it's going to read
一个值和它要 读
meaning print the value of B and the
意打印的B和值
other thread is going to do the opposite
其他线程会反其道而行之
it's going to write assigned a value to
它会写分配值
be in prison the value of a and so now
在监狱里的价值，因此现在
the question is what are the possible
问题是什么是可能的
outputs for this program and so there's
对这一计划的输出 ，所以有
a model that sort of the accepted
模型所接受的那种
standard called sequential consistency
标准叫做顺序一致性
which means that these events can occur
这意味着，可能会发生这些事件
well that these that within a single
还有，这些是 在一个单一的
thread things have to occur in the
螺纹事情已经发生
sequential order of that thread but
该线程的顺序，但
across threads whether write a a write B
跨线程是否 写入AA写乙
occurs first is completely arbitrary and
先发生完全是任意的 和
similarly whether writing of B occurs
类似B的写入是否发生
between
之间
these two actions are before is also
这两个动作都是以前 也
arbitrary so what what it means is you
任意的，它的意思就是你
can take two different threads and you
可以采取两种 不同的线程 和你
can interleave their their events in any
可交错他们自己在任何事件
way but you should be able to pull out
的方式，但你应该能够拉出来
of that interleaving the sequential
该交错 顺序的
order of either of both of the two
任两个两个的顺序
threads so when you do that you end up
线程所以当你做， 你最终会
you can enumerate an example like this
你可以列举这样一个例子
all the possibilities you can say well
所有你 能说好准备
look it first is either going to be
看它首先是要么将是
right a or right view
右一或右视图
let's pick right a so now the next event
让我们挑右一所以现在下一个事件
will be either a read of B or write of B
将或者 B的 B或 写 的读
and then if I if I do write a write read
然后，如果我如果我不写一写读
B so I've completed this thread and so
B上我已经完成了这个线程等
now the only possibility is to write to
现在唯一的可能性是写
B and read a and so forth you work out
B和阅读等你的工作
all the possible things you get six
所有可能的事情，你 送六
different event ordering and then what
不同的事件 排序，然后什么
will be printed is well first of all
将要打印的是很好首先
whether you print before a will depend
无论你打印前将取决于
on the relative ordering of those two
在这两个的相对顺序
threads so that's shown them showing the
线程所以这表明，它们显示
B value in blue and the red value in red
蓝色B值和红色的红色值
the I'm sorry the a value in red and
在对不起红色的值，
you'll get these different possibilities
你会得到这些不同的可能性
these are all the six possible outputs
这些都是六个可能的输出
of this program but you'll see that
这个程序 ， 但你会看到 ，
there are two two other outputs one
有两种其它两个输出的一个
could imagine that won't arise one is to
可以想象， 不会 出现 一个是
print one hundred and one in other words
打印换句话说101
to have them both print the original
有他们两个打印原稿
values of these two variables and that's
这两个变量的值，这就是
impossible because I have to have done
不可能的，因为我已经都做
at least one right before I can reach
之前，我可以达到至少一个权
either of these two print statements
这两种报表打印
right so it's not possible for these to
右 所以它不可能为 这些来
still be in their original values when I
仍然是在原来的值时，我
hit these print statements
打这些打印语句
and whichever order I hit these two so
和订单为准我打这两个如此
those two are impossible so that's the
这两个是不可能的所以这是
idea of sequential consistency that
的 顺序一致性想法
there's some a very large number but of
有一些非常大的数目，但的
possible outputs of a program but in any
在任何一个方案，但可能的输出
case they can't violate the ordering
情况下，他们可以在不违反排序
implied by the individual threads so
由单个线程，以便暗示
you'd say okay that seems like pretty
你会说 好这似乎 是相当
obvious thing but actually if you think
显而易见的事情，但实际上，如果你认为
from a hardware perspective it's not
从硬件的角度来看它不是
that trivial to make that happen so let
那微不足道要做到这一点 所以让
me just throw a show you a scenario of
我只是扔你展示的场景
multi-core hardware that would violate
这将违反 多核 硬件
sequential consistency assume that each
顺序一致性假设每个
of our threads has its own private cache
我们的线程都有自己的专用高速缓存
and so if I execute this statement what
所以如果 我执行该语句什么
I'll do is I will grab a copy of a from
我要做的是我会抢的副本从
the main memory and bring it into my
主存储器 ，并把它变成我的
cache and I will assign this new value
高速缓存和我将赋予该 新值
to it and similarly thread two will grab
它和同样线程 两人将抢
a copy of it of B and an update that and
B的一个副本和更新这一点 ，
now if I do my two print statements if
现在，如果我做我的两个打印语句 ，如果
thread two picks up the value from the
线程2个拾起从价值
memory not knowing that thread one as a
内存不知道该线程一个作为
modified copy of that value then it
该值的修改后的副本则
would naturally print one and similarly
自然会打印一张，同样
if if thread one picked up a copy of B
如果如果一个线程拿起 B 的副本
from main memory it would print 100 so
从主内存 ， 它将打印 100，
we'd see exactly this unallowable
我们会看到的正是这种不能允许
execution and the reason is because each
执行其原因是因为每个
of these threads have their own private
这些线程拥有自己的私人
copies of these variables and they're
这些变量的副本，并且他们
not properly synchronized but you could
不能正常同步，但 你可以
see in a hardware scenario it would be
看到一个硬件的情况这将是
easy to build this hardware and make
容易 建立这样的硬件， 使
that mistake so how does it work in a in
这个错误所以它是如何 在工作中
a multi-core processor well they have a
多核处理器以及它们具有
trick they call it Snoopy caches and
诱骗他们称之为史努比缓存和
it's a little bit like the readers
它就像读者一点点
writers of synchronization that you're
同步的作家，你是
working on for your proxy
正在为您的代理
that you want to make it so that if
你想让它这样，如果
everyone's just reading some shared
每个人都只是阅读一些共享
value they should be able to get copies
值应该能够得到副本
into their own caches to optimize the
到自己的高速缓存来优化
performance of it but if one of them
它的性能，但如果他们中的一个
wants to write to it it needs to get an
想要写 它，它需要得到一个
exclusive copy of it and lock out any
它独特的副本，并锁定任何
other thread from accessing that either
访问，要么其他线程
to read it or to write it from long
读它或将它 从 长 写
enough to make the update and so they
足以使更新，所以他们
they have a protocol where they tag
他们有一个协议，其中 它们标签
actually and these tags are at the level
其实这些标签是在水平
of cache lines typically so the tagged
的高速缓存行通常所以 标记
cache line in main memory with its state
在其状态的主存储器的高速缓存行
and the typical state would be invalid
和典型的 状态将是无效的
it's shared or its exclusive so shared
它的共享或者其独有所以共享
means that there can be copies of it but
意味着 可以有它的副本，但
they can only be read only copy an
他们只能是只读 的复制
exclusive meaning that it's exclusively
独特的意义，它是专
available to a single thread so this is
提供给一个单独的线程，所以这是
built into them the hardware of a
内置到他们的硬件
multi-core processor so what will happen
多核处理器 ，从而会 发生 什么
then is in order to do a write to a
然后就是为了 做一个写入
thread one will acquire an exclusive
一个线程将获得独家
copy of this element and that actually
这个元素的副本， 并且实际
tagging happens down here at the main
标签在这里发生倒在主
memory and in the cache both and
内存和高速缓存和两个
similarly if if thread two wants a to
同样，如果如果线程2想要一个到
write to B it must get an exclusive copy
写到B就必须获得 专有副本
of that and then when the read occurs
的那个，然后当读出发生
what happens is actually this cache miss
发生了什么实际上是这个高速缓存未命中
will send out a signal on a bus to
将发出一个信号， 一个总线上
shared communication medium saying I
共享通信媒体说我
want to read a and instead of the main
要阅读和的不是主
memory responding to it actually it will
内存响应它实际上会
that result will be supplied by the
该结果将被供给
other cache and it will convert the
其他高速缓存，它会转换
state of this element to being a shared
该元件的状态，以被共享
element locally but you'll see that the
本地元素，但你会看到，
main memory
主内存
it isn't updated yet it goes through the
这还没有更新它穿过
whole right-back protocol you've already
你已经整个右后卫协议
seen but and sometimes it will update
观察，但有时它会更新
that there's different implementations
这有不同的实现
but this is why it's called a Snoopy
但是，这就是为什么它 被称为史努比
cache is that it basically thread 2 is
缓存是，它基本上线程2
is peeking into or getting it access to
被偷看或得到它访问
information that's available in thread
在线程的可用信息
ones cache and so now thread 2 will
那些缓存，所以现在线程2将
correctly get a copy of a that's in the
正确得到的副本那是在
shared state and the same goes would be
共享状态 和同样是
it will snip over and thread two well
它会剪断了和线程两个 著名
one will get a readable copy these are
一个将得到一个可读的拷贝这些都是
now all marked as shared state and so if
现在所有标记为共享状态 ，所以如果
if either of them want to write they'd
如果其中任何想写他们会
have to now basically get exclusive
必须现在基本上得到独家
access to it and that would have to then
访问它，并且必须 再
disable the copy and the other in the
禁用副本和其他的
other locations so you can imagine this
其他位置，这样你 能想象这
protocol being non-trivial actually to
协议是不平凡的实际到
get right and to implement it gets way
马上及其实施 方式得到
more complicated than this with all the
比这更复杂 的所有
variations on it so but it's become the
它的变化左右，但它已经成为了
norm in multi-core hardware design but
在多核的硬件设计规范，但
it's actually part of the factor that
它实际上是要素的一部分
limits the court count on a processor
限制了处理器在球场上的计数
because just the hardware involved in
因为刚涉足硬件
keeping the consistency across the
保持跨越的一致性
caches is non-trivial it has to work
缓存是不平凡的它工作
very fast we're talking at the cash rate
很快我们在现金利率交谈
access speeds so there's not a lot of
访问速度所以没有很多的
time involved in there so actually
涉及的时间在那里所以实际上
implementing this stuff making it run
实现这个东西使它运行
making it scale across say eight cores
使其规模横跨说八个核
10 cores 16 cores is not not a trivial
10个芯16个核不是不是一个简单的
time but that goes on in the background
时间，但在背景的推移
and so you can for most systems nowadays
所以你可以为时下最系统
you can assume that there's some memory
你可以假设， 有一些记忆
consistency model that you can program
一致性模型，你可以 编程
to that's supported by the hardware of
至由 硬件 支持
the system and that this serial
该系统和 该系列
serializability that's referred to as a
多数民众赞成被称为串行化
third of the the easiest to understand
第三的最容易理解的
these others are a little bit more
这些人是 多 一点点
nuanced
细致入微
look if that fell off the bottom here
看，如果在 这里摔了下来底部
anything tonight
今天晚上什么事
thank you
谢谢
that's it okay so just to wrap that up
就这样 好了，只是来包装 起来
then it gives you a flavor of and you
那么它给 你的和你的味道
can see that getting programs to run
可以看到，让程序运行
fast through multi-threading is not not
快速通过多线程是不是不
easy you often have to rewrite your
方便你经常要重写
application you have to think about the
应用程序，你必须想想
algorithm you have to worry about
算法你不必担心
debugging it as you've already
调试它，你已经
discovered at both the the shell lab in
在无论是在 外壳 的实验室发现
the proxy lab that concurrency where you
代理实验室并发性，你
can't predict the order of events makes
无法预测事件的顺序使得
it much more difficult to debug code so
它更难以调试代码，以便
all these factors come in and you have
所有这些因素进来，你有
to have some understanding of the
拥有的一些理解
underlying mechanisms that are used and
所使用的基本机制和
what their performance implications are
什么他们的性能影响是
so in particular let me just observe
所以特别让我观察
here that if I'm like doing
在这里，如果我喜欢做
synchronization across threads like you
遇到像你线程同步
saw that original one where they are
看到原来他们在哪里
fighting over this global variable P sum
争夺这个全局变量 P总和
or whatever it was called you can
或不管它被称为可以
imagine these the caches in this battle
想象这些在这场战斗中的高速缓存
with each other to try and get exclusive
互相尝试 并获得独家
access to this single memory of value
获得 的值这单个存储器
and because each one is running as fast
因为每个人的奔跑速度一样快
as it possibly can but each one requires
因为它 可能可以 但每一个需要
getting exclusive copy writing to it and
获得独家文案写作它和
releasing it so that locking mechanism
释放它，以便锁定机制
is flying back and forth between these
在它们之间 来回飞
caches and it's really not very fast so
高速缓存和它真的 不是非常快，所以
that the kind of thing is why of and
的那种东西就是为什么和
also as an application programmer you're
也可以作为应用程序的程序员你
making calls semaphore call bounces you
拨打电话通话信号您反弹
up into the OS kernel which is a cost
成在OS内核 是一种成本
involved so this thing has all the bad
参与所以这个东西有所有的坏
of all the things that make programs not
所有这使程序不是东西
run the way you really like them to so
运行方式你真的喜欢他们 这么
that's one of the challenges in parallel
这是并行的挑战之一
programming is how do you actually make
编程是你如何实际上使
use of the parallelism that's there
使用并行这是有
without getting bogged down by the
没有陷入困境由
cost of the various mechanisms of
的各种机制的成本
control huh so anyways this is part of
控制呵呵所以反正这是一部分
what you have to appreciate and
你有什么体会和
understand as a programmer is how these
了解作为一个程序员是如何将这些
things work at a level deep enough that
事情在 深 的程度 不够 ， 工作
you'll have some sense of what makes
您将有 一定意义 的是什么使
programs run faster or slower where the
程序运行更快或更慢的地方
mistakes could lie so that's just a
错误可能在于所以这只是一个
little little flavor of a much bigger
一个更大一点一点味道
topic so that's it for today
话题所以这是它今天